var pos = 0, test, test_status, question, choice, choices, choiceA, choiceB, choiceC, correct=0, name = 0; 
var quizAnswers =[];
var questions= [
{
	question: "Who won the premier league in the 2015-16 season?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Leicster City", //Correct answer
	// Possible Choices
	answer0: "Chelsea",
	answer1: "Leicster City",
	answer2: "Man Utd",
	answer3: "Liverpol"
},
{
	question: "What was the score as Ireland beat New Zealand in Chicago?",//question
	correctAnswer: "40-29", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Choices
	answer0: "36-21",
	answer1: "40-29",
	answer2: "40-32",
	answer3: "33-21"
}, 
{
	question: "Who did Connacht beat in the Pro 12 Final?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Leinster", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Choices
	answer0: "Munster",
	answer1: "Glasgow",
	answer2: "Leinster",
	answer3: "Ulster"
}, 
{
	question: "Who scored the winner for Portugal in the 2016 European Final?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Eder", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Choices
	answer0: "Ronaldo",
	answer1: "Eder",
	answer2: "Pepe",
	answer3: "Mario"
},
{
	question: "Who won Senior footballer of the year for 2016?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Lee Keegan", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Choices
	answer0: "Ciararn Kilkenny",
	answer1: "Brian Fenton",
	answer2: "Diarmuid Connolly",
	answer3: "Lee Keegan"
},
{
	question: "Who won Senior hurler of the year for 2016?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Austin Gleeson", //Correct Answer
	//Possible Choices
	answer0: "Austin Gleeson",
	answer1: "Padraic Maher",
	answer2: "Seamus Callinan",
	answer3: "Richie Hogan"
},
{
	question: "How many medals did Ireland win at the Olympics?",//question
	correctAnswer: "2", //Correct Answer
	//Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "2",
	answer1: "3",
	answer2: "4",
	answer3: "5"
},
{
	question: "Where are the O Donovan brothers from?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Cork", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Limerick",
	answer1: "Cork",
	answer2: "Dublin",
	answer3: "Donegal"
},
{
	question: "Who won the RBS six nations grand slam?",//question
	correctAnswer: "England", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Ireland",
	answer1: "England",
	answer2: "Wales",
	answer3: "France"
},
{
	question: "In what stadium did Ireland beat New Zealand?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Soldier Field", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Wrigley Stadium",
	answer1: "St Marys",
	answer2: "Soldier Field",
	answer3: "Rockine Stadium"
},
{
	question: "Who is the current Dublin football manager?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Jim Gavin", // Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Jim Gavin",
	answer1: "Pat Gilory",
	answer2: "Barney Rock",
	answer3: "Alan Brogan"
},
{
	question: "Who provided the assist for Robbie Bradys goal vs Italy?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Wes Hoolohan", //Correct Answer
	//Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Aidan McGeady",
	answer1: "Seamus Coleman",
	answer2: "Robbie Keane",
	answer3: "Wes Hoolohan"
},
{
	question: "Who did Real Madrid beat in the Uefa Champions League Final?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Atletico Madrid", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Atletico Madrid",
	answer1: "Barcelona",
	answer2: "Bayern Munich",
	answer3: "Chelsea"
},	
{	
	question: "In golf, who won the Brittish Open?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Henrik Stenson", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Justin Speith",
	answer1: "Rory Mcilory",
	answer2: "Henrik Stenson",
	answer3: "Sergio Garica"
},
{
	question: "What age was Anthony Foley when he passed away?",//question
	correctAnswer: "42", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "40",
	answer1: "41",
	answer2: "42",
	answer3: "43"
},
{
	question: "Who did Tippeary beat in Munster Hurling Final?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Waterford", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Clare",
	answer1: "Waterford",
	answer2: "Cork",
	answer3: "Limerick"
},
{
	question: "Which of these boxers turned professional after the Olympics?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Michael Conlon", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Michael Conlon",
	answer1: "Paddy Barnes",
	answer2: "Kenny Egan",
	answer3: "John Joe Nevin"
},
{
	question: "Which of these Kerry footballers retired in 2016?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Aidan O Mahony", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Aidan O Mahony",
	answer1: "Paul Galvin",
	answer2: "Kieran Donaghy",
	answer3: "Tomas O Se"
},
{
	question: "How many years have Mayo gone without Sam Maguire?",//question
	correctAnswer: "65", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "55",
	answer1: "60",
	answer2: "65",
	answer3: "70"
},
{
	question: "Who is the current manager of the Republic soccer team?",//question
	correctAnswer: "Martin O Neill", //Correct Answer
	// Possible Outcomes
	answer0: "Roy Keane",
	answer1: "Martin O Neill",
	answer2: "Kenny Cunningham",
	answer3: "Brian Kerr"
},

];


function _(x)
{ 
    return document.getElementById(x);
} 
//Setting underscore equal to document.getElementById (handy shortcut)
		
function percent()
{
    var perc = Math.round((correct/questions.length)*100);
    return perc;//gets percentage and returns to form
}

function renderQuestion()
{
	test = _("test");
	if(pos >=questions.length)//If position is greater or equal to the number of questions
	{
		test.innerHTML = "<h2>You got "+correct+" of "+questions.length+" questions correct(" +percent() + "%)</h2>"; //Print # correct out of 20
		_("test_status").innerHTML += " Thank you for completing the quiz";//Print "thank you...."
		pos = 0;
		correct = 0;
		return false;
	}
	var bar=document.getElementById("progressBar");//Progress bar value
	
	_("test_status").innerHTML = "Question "+(pos+1)+" of "+questions.length;
	
	bar.value = (pos+1)//Progress bar increments as we go through questions, starts at 1
	
	question = questions[pos].question;//question is in position 0 in the array(zero indexed)
	choiceA = questions[pos].answer0;//Choice A is in position 1 in the array
	choiceB = questions[pos].answer1;//Choice B is in position 2 in the array
	choiceC = questions[pos].answer2;//Choice C is in position 3 in the array
	choiceD = questions[pos].answer3;//Choice D is in position 4 in the array
	test.innerHTML = "<h3>"+question+"</h3>";
	test.innerHTML += "<input type='radio' name='choices' value='"+choiceA+"' checked> "+choiceA+" <br>"; //Radio button
	test.innerHTML += "<input type='radio' name='choices' value='"+choiceB+"' checked> "+choiceB+" <br>"; //Radio button
	test.innerHTML += "<input type='radio' name='choices' value='"+choiceC+"' checked> "+choiceC+" <br>"; //Radio button
	test.innerHTML += "<input type='radio' name='choices' value='"+choiceD+"' checked> "+choiceD+" <br>"; //Radio button
	test.innerHTML += "<button onclick='checkAnswer()'>Submit Answer</button>"; 
	}
	
function checkAnswer()
{
	choices = document.getElementsByName("choices"); //Creates an array
	for(var i=0; i<choices.length; i++)//variable i=0, when i is less than the length of the coice, increment it by one
	{
		if(choices[i].checked) //if a choice is checked
		{
			choice = choices[i].value; //Take the value of that choice and put it into choice
		}
	}
	if(choice == questions[pos].correctAnswer)//If the value of choices is equal to position 4
	{
		alert('Correct!');//Alert correct
		correct++;//Increment your correct answer by one
	}
	else//or else//
	{
		alert('Sorry wrong answer. The correct answer is ' + questions[pos].correctAnswer);
	}
	pos++; //Increment position by one ie go on to the nest question
	
	renderQuestion(); //go to render question again
}
		


//Call the question with an event handler
window.addEventListener("load", renderQuestion, false);